Abraham: When changes are made to
a system or network there is the
potential to create new vulnerabilities.
It is therefore imperative that
further testing and retesting
is done to mitigate this.
Nicole: This may be done on
a regular basis and is called
remediation verification testing.
Remediation verification testing
makes sure that any vulnerabilities
identified during pen testing
have been dealt with successfully.
It focusses on ensuring that issues that
arose have been properly identified,
fixed and are no longer a threat.
Abraham: It works by attempting
to reproduce each vulnerability
and then checking if it is fixed.
Insurers and regulators often
require this to be done by an
independent authority to make sure
the testing and solution is robust.
Nicole: A penetration test can only
however, validate that an organisations
IT systems are not vulnerable to any
known issues as of the day of the test.
Unless tests are done on a regular basis,
vulnerability can last in a system for
some time before it is checked again.
How are the outcomes of cyber
security testing reported?
Abraham: Once testing is done the most
common form of reporting is the detailed
reports usually sent to senior management.
Smaller tests and regular scans
may be reported as memos, incident
logs or as a short report.
Reports are responsible for detailing all
the tasks performed by a security tester
or ethical hacker and are responsible
for detailing key findings and steps
needed to act on these by remediation.
Nicole: Reports may be viewed by senior
management, IT teams, clients or even
the regulators and should be clear and
concise whilst setting out any details
of the problems and the solutions.
Abraham: A good report should also
include a summary or overview of any
findings and recommendations as well
as a comprehensive detailed list
of issues and proposed solutions.
This then should make it clear to
all levels of interested parties.
Nicole: A test report should include:
• any security issues that are uncovered,
• an assessment of the level of risk that
each vulnerability exposes the system to.
• a method or resolving each issue.
• An opinion on the accuracy of the
vulnerability assessment and advice
on how to improve the process.
The process of debriefing is also very
important, and vulnerabilities can be
discussed according to their severity
and if a test shows vulnerabilities
then solutions can be found.
Abraham: So, why should the outcomes
of cyber security testing be reported?
There are many reasons for reporting
the outcomes of cyber security
testing but whatever the reason
these results should only be
shared with those who need to know.
They can include sensitive highly
confidential information which should
only be made available to trusted parties.
Nicole: However, a summary version
of a report can be more widely shared
detailing the scope and approach of an
attack and how this can be mitigated.
Abraham: Websites, organisations
and software developers often
offer a ‘bug bounty’ to uncover
issues and vulnerabilities that may
impact their product or systems.
For those who find complex security
vulnerabilities the payout can be
high but on average payouts are low.
Nicole: There are also companies that
offer the service of connecting ‘bug
bounty hunters’ to companies to help
with finding their vulnerability issues.
However, for some organisations, there
may be other reasons for reporting the
outcomes of cyber security testing.
One of these may be regulatory to
demonstrate to the appropriate authorities
that they are taking steps to identify
and eliminate any vulnerabilities.
They may also be required by
regulatory bodies to conduct regular
testing especially after a breach.
Abraham: A key principle of GDPR
regulations is that personal data
is processed securely, and all
systems and services have the
correct security to maintain this.
The National Cyber Security Centre
[NCSC] even offers a service to
organisations to report cyber
security incidents simplifying
the reporting landscape for users.
Nicole: It is therefore especially
important that if an organisation has
had a data breach it shows that it
is taking all the appropriate steps
to stop this from happening again.
Abraham: Reporting testing results
is the best way that an organisation
can regain trust after a breach
and reassure their clients and
customers that their system is secure.
Nicole: This can also help an organization
to better plan for any future threats
and allocate the appropriate resources
to help prevent this happening.